Dilan Patel

139 St. Pauls Avenue, Harrow, Middlesex, HA3 9PT **E-mail:** dilan07patel@gmail.com · **Mobile:** 07743605567

Summary

An enthusiastic, responsible and versatile individual who possesses an organised and focused approach to work, Dilan can carry out tasks in an efficient manner to provide results. He can break down an issue into its core constituents to better analyse the problem and provide an efficient solution. From past experiences, he also is a natural communicator with skills suitable for a professional environment and teamwork. Also, being a fast and enthusiastic learner, Dilan is willing to undergo any training necessary that will allow him to upskill to work more effectively and provide solutions.

Skills

Soft

- Effective communication
- Teamwork
- Creative
- Fast learner
- Adaptable
- Work under pressure

Technical

- Object Oriented Design
- Front-End HTML, CSS/SCSS, JS
- Back-End C#, SQL
- Version Control Git, GitHub, GitBash
- Agile / Scrum
- Photoshop

Experience

Technical Consultant - Sparta Global

February 2020 - September 2020

- Specialised in C# development working with a client of Sparta Global
- Worked in agile environment with scrum teams of 10, with exposure to agile ceremonies such as daily standup, sprint planning, retrospectives, reviews and regression stages
- Main duties involved completing user stories focused on back-end C# development and SQL but also Java. Also front-end based user stories
 - Tool and technologies used: Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio, IntelliJ IDEA,
 Visual Studio Code, C#, ASP.NET, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript
 - Version control tools: Git, GitBash
 - o Collaboration tools: Jira, Confluence, Outlook, Skype, Teams
 - o Business tools: Microsoft Office, Outlook, Skype
- Minor duties involving testing and regression testing. Using tools such as Sentry.IO to monitor and sift through errors on testing environments and debug and fix them before merging to live

Sales Associate - Rumble's School Uniform

June 2018 - September 2018

- · Provided customer service, ensuring customers feel welcome and put first with any of their needs
- Maintained a clean shop floor environment and handled stock deliveries with other colleagues
- Worked on till, processing purchases, returns and other customer enquiries

Education

Trainee Consultant - Sparta Global

October 2019 - January 2020

- Took part in a C# development training course
- Learnt technical skills such as Object Oriented Design, Test Driven Development with NUnit Testing,
 Web Design, Database Design with SQL
- Version control with Github, GitBash
- Learnt the Agile Framework and Methodology and put in practice with various projects

BSc Computer Science (with Soft. Engineering) - University of Hertfordshire

September 2016 - September 2019

Grade: Upper Second (2:1)

- Created web-based music streaming application for final year project
- Used tools such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, SQL, JSON
- Ensured software engineering principles and practices were used
- Used Agile methodology.
- Used Github for version control and Trello for project management
- Conducted research on different types of applications to see which was best suited for a music streaming application.

A-Levels - Kingsbury High School Sixth Form

September 2013 - July 2015

Grades: Math (B), Biology (C), Chemistry (D)

- Managed after school robotics club for lower school students with two peers and occasional help from senior member of staff
- Gave experience in leadership and managing responsibilities.

GCSEs - Kingsbury High School

September 2008 - July 2013

Grades:

Math, Biology, Chemistry, Physics, Geography (5 A) English Literature, English Language, German (4 B) Electronics (1 C)

IT, Further IT (2 Distinctions)

• Part of the school's basketball team in year 7 which helped encourage team-building.

Hobbies

- Possessing a creative side, Dilan enjoys working on art whether digital or through drawing. From a
 young age, he has enjoyed drawing and with an interest in technology, he learnt more about digital
 tools such as Photoshop, Cinema 4D, Sony Vegas and After Effects. Combining these tools with his
 passion for art, he self-taught himself how to use these tools and created graphics/media which
 eventually progressed into providing it as a service to clients to also providing tutorials on YouTube on
 how to use these tools.
- He also enjoys producing music on FL Studio, after teaching himself how to use the application and the fundamentals of music.
- Leading a healthy lifestyle, he enjoys exercising and maintaining a workout regime to improve health and self-confidence.